Shashi Kant

Full stack developer (MERN)

- © 7860735070 9559835359
- skntjee@gmail.com
- https://skntmax.co.in/
- (a) Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin .com/in/shashi-kant-5a1710185/

- (m) 14/07/1998
- (Noida



Objective

I have 2 years of experience in web development including my internship from internshala .I had started my journey since third year of my college days and i created so many projects all by self using laravel and in core php . After some time i swtiched to MERN strack development and created these projects such as chat application in node js ,Youtube Clone in react js ,Content managment system in react js etc.. deployed it to cloud as well , and after completing my graduation i joined this organisation in Nov 2021 as full stack developer .

Currently i am working in value innovation labs situated in noida. And here i have worked with 3 government projects and created 5 - 6 modules , all of them are currently in running state . some of my projects name which i am currently working with is CCIL (cement corporation of india), EPIL (Engineering interprize project),Rozgar.com (naukri portal) and last one was FISCI (A college portal site for managing students data).

apart from that i runs my own blog name called techymaxx.com since last past two years all by own . A full stack developer authorised by intnernshaal and Linkedin . Hakcer rank certified in SQL .

seeing to further boost and solve real world problems by that all skils i have aquired til now .



Education

CSE/B.Tech

CHHATRAPATI SHAHU JI MAHARAJ UNIVERSITY (CSJMU KANPUR) Aug 2017 - Aug 2021

computer science and engineering

SWAMI HARSEWANAND PUBLIC SCHOOL (VARANASI)

July 205 - july 2016

12th Science



Work Experience

VALUE INNOVATION LABS 2021 - Now

Noida

Full Stack developer (MERN)

A

Some Live Mini Projects

1. CONTACT - LIST (PERSITENCE REDUX) 2022 - 2022

https://react-demo44.netlify.app/contact

Using React/redux

2. TODO LIST (PERSITENCE REDUX)

https://react-demo44.netlify.app/todo-redux

Using React/reduxList

2022 - 2022

3. PERSONAL BLOG 2022 - 2022

https://react-demo44.netlify.app/blog
Using (React js , node-js , mongo-db , google drive)



Interests

I like singing, cricket and travelling ..



Skills

Language	English, Hindi
Programming Language	javascript , c++, java , python ,
Backend languages	Node js , php
Framework	Next js , react Native , express js , flask api
API	Rest api
Auth	Auth0 (Google, linkedin, facebook, twitter etc)
Web Techonlogies :	React-Js , HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material Ui, fluent UI, Reactstrap , Jquery ,Redux , react-query , react-virtualization
Tam Work	SEO , Negotiation and Teamwork
Database	Mysql , Mongo , Postgres
AWS	EC2 instances , s3 bucket
Deployement	Netlify and AWS, docker, Jenkins, Linux environment
Operating System	windows and Linux
Programming Concepts	Data structure and algorithms



Enterprise Level Projects

1 (CCIL, **TECH STACK: React js , Node js , Postgres**): it's a government experprise project known as cement cororation of India . bascailly it's an employee , file and leave management system of this own company . like file forwarding to multiple departments at multiple level and getting approval by approving authority at the end , applying leave , monitoting of leave , giving access of such several modules feature exists in this app .

In this project mainly i have worked on fixing bugs in file management and leave modules . apart from that i have created a **Committe Module** . where file will only be forwarded onl when untill and unless all the committe members mark the file and give their own discription of that file . I have been working on this project about months .

- 2. (EPIL , TECH STACK: React js , Node js , Postgres): It's very similar to above project but modififed version of CCIL. generally known as Engineering Enterprise project . but it includedes some other modules with the old one . like E-filing modules , Knowledge management module , DAK maagement , E-toor , Medical reimbursment . which was totally intiated by me from scratch . And in this projects i have created E-toor module and Medical reimbursment module . Knowledge management . Apart from that and except all that modules made by me i haved done fixing and enhancement , like in E-filling , Leave module ,, Dak module as well . Overall these all modules are currently in running state and used by government employees of EPIL . I have been working on this project since last 1.5 years .
- **3.(ROZGAR.COM , TECH STACK: Next js , Node js , Mysql):** It's our own company's project very similar to naukari.com but have inluded some different feature .latest version is still not live due to developing stage . In this project i have done data migration of 70,000 jobs with fully mapped with category , role , industry , employeer id , location , job title from the

older version of rozgar.com . which was previusly running in mongo db where as new one is runnning on mysql db . later we migrated this whole web app on next js for SEO purpose and site to be ranked on any serach engine easily. And later on build some other modules such as resume making , summary and cover letter generator using AI also integrated grammerly .

4.(HRMS, TECH STACK: React js, Node js, Postgres): it's also our own company's project bascailly a employee management system . where i have worked with payroll module.

5.(recruiter.rozgar.com and rozgar.com ,TECH STACK: Next js , Node js , Mysql): Have integreated Zoom API in rozgar recruiter section and in candidate portal where interveiwer can take their candidate interview on their own plateform without any third party apps such as zoom or google meet.



Achievement

- 1. Digital marketing certification awarded by Google
- 2. Got 58.79% in TCS NQT exam
- 3. Runs a website called https://techymaxx.com
- 4. Hacker rank SQL certified
- 5. full stack developer certified by internshala



PersonAL Projects	
1. Youtube Clone app (using React and youtube data v3 api) Source Code: https://github.com/skntmax/youtube_clone	10/2021
2. Real Time chat application (Using Node js , handlebar template Engine , Mysql , Express , HTML , CSS) Source Code : https://github.com/skntmax/socket_app	10/2021
3. Todo list (using pure javascript) Source Code : https://github.com/skntmax/toDoList	07/2021
4. mp3 music player (using pure javascript) Source Code : https://github.com/skntmax/music_player	07/2021
5. Blog management system (usng node js express mongo) Source Code : https://github.com/skntmax/blog	09/2021
6. Employee managment system (Using React js) Source Code : https://github.com/skntmax/	07/2021
7. tolet system (Using Laravel) Source Code : https://github.com/skntmax/to-let	07/2021

The main aim of this project was to solve the problem of bachelor or for any person who is searching for rooms to stay at local level or you can say in cheaper prices. Cause most of the these students come from very pool family so that they are not able to pay such high price rent for their survival. That's why I tried to build a system which is able to solve not more but atleast some of problem in their life .

